Methods of Counting Defect Opportunities
Hello, Mike Harry back with you again. Where we’re exploring defect opportunities.
And we’re going to take a look at a few more examples here. Let's move forward here.
What we’re looking at here, is a simulation in a bank.
Of people coming and going to the different tellers.
And so, let's take an idea here.
And that idea is this, every person is an opportunity.
So when we ask ourselves the following question,
when this person, the customer, approaches this teller,
what must go right? We see, the inverse of that is what could go wrong?
And let's say that we identify twenty-five things.
And through the use of customer satisfaction surveys,
or direct observation through cameras, and interviews, etc.,
we can establish the number of things that went wrong, i.e. defects.
And of course the opportunity count would be the number of individuals that actually come in
and arrive at a tellers desk. That's one example.
Let’s take a look at another.
In this case produce testing. What they've done is there testing lettuce.
And you can see them there doing that.
There's the gentleman with the bag of lettuce here, that draws a sample.
To look for bacteriological growth, in that sample.
There's the little sample right there, of which he's observing.
And there might be, let's say, several different strains of bacteria they’re looking for.
So, every one of those strains is an opportunity, per sample.
Just like a solder joint, that little piece right there is equivalent to a solder joint.
Has defect opportunities.
And of course, a classic one, machining.
To where we're looking at
a tool coming in here to drill a hole.
Well, the hole has to be round.
See, concentricity. That's an opportunity. That's a CTQ.
So, in general we can draw this conclusion,
any CTQ, anything that is critical to quality.
See, the solder joint is critical to value,
but one of the six categories is critical to quality.
Each defect category is a critical to quality characteristic.
And some of those defect categories are continuous by nature
and others are discrete, pass-fail.
But at the bottom line, at the end of the day, we rate them all as pass-fail,
for purposes of defect counting.
Well in this case, concentricity here, is a continuous measure.
And by measuring it, getting the
specific measured value, and comparing it to the standard.
If it's within the spec limits, it passes. If it don't, it fails. So again, zero-one.
And there we see yet more machining going on, a different type of machining operation.
So, all of those have CTQ’s.
Like what is going on right here.
There's supposed to be a radius, maybe, on the edge of the material.
And he’s putting that radius on there.
That's a critical to quality characteristic.
The same thing back here with this machine. Here, we’ll let it run.
As it’s operating away, maybe it's milling a slot through here.
And the slot should be of a certain width and certain depth. Well, there’s two different CTQ’s,
two critical to quality characteristics, two defect opportunities.
So, with that thought, once again, we can see how it can be applied
in the industrial world as well as the commercial world.
And remember, it's very, very simple.
All we have to do. Define the product.
Create a hierarchical tree of what comprises that product.
Down at the bottom of the tree is a product element, like a solder joint.
That element has k number of defect categories.
Every defect category constitutes an opportunity.
And from there, we can compute the Sigma, or the yield, or any other number of metrics.
But at the end of the day we’re looking, where Six Sigma is concerned, at defects
per opportunity, defects per million opportunities.
And with that, that concludes our discussion on defect opportunities.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.